mgh@mghachem.com

https://www.mghachem.com

AROUT

I design experiences for both the digital and the physical world. I create designs that emphasize ease of use and accessibility, and provide valuable solutions to end-users problems.

I believe good design is innovative, functional, clean, and honest.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

English (First language) Arabic (Native) Spanish (B1-B2 Level)

CRAFT

User needs research . Ideation . Sketching . Concept development . Illustration . Design research . Usercentered design . Human factors . Wireframing . Prototyping . Digital modelling . User Testing .

SOFTWARE

Balsamiq . Adobe XD . Invision . Illustrator . InDesign . Photoshop . Rhinoceros . AutoCAD . V-Ray rendering . Unity3D .

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

 $\mathsf{HTML} \, \boldsymbol{.} \, \mathsf{CSS} \, \boldsymbol{.} \, \mathsf{Javascript} \, \boldsymbol{.} \, \mathsf{Python} \, \boldsymbol{.} \, \mathsf{C\#}$

EDUCATION

AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF SHARJAH (SHARJAH, UAE)

Bachelor's of Architecture . N.A.A.B Accredited . 2014

I completed 178 credits split between architecture, visual communication, and product design. I was the chapter president of the American Institute of Architecture Students.

UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA - DARDEN SCHOOL OF BUSINESS

Digital Product Management Specialisation • 2020

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, IRVINE

Project Management Principles and Practices Specialisation . 2020

UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN

User Experience Research and Design Specialisation • 2020

WORK EXPERIENCE

TINKERLIST.TV (LEUVEN, BELGIUM, REMOTE)

User Experience Designer . 2021 - Present

I work closely with the product, customer success, and business team to create a platform revamp that will make a one-man-band television production a walk in the park by leveraging automation and embedding sophisticated intelligence into the software.

ECOMZ (BEIRUT, LEBANON)

Customer Experience and Senior User Experience Designer . 2020 - 2021

Design lead on the Website Builder 2.0, lead on the platform UI/UX revamp, developed and maintained the website and Zendesk website.

FREELANCE DESIGNER (REMOTE)

Architect . Visual Designer . User Experience Designer . 2014 - 2020

I actively worked as a freelance architect, visual and UX designer for multiple clients across different countries and a variety of media.

BH ENGINEERING OFFICE (BEIRUT, LEBANON)

Architect Branding Designer Procurement Officer 2015 - 2019

I was the architectural lead and main liasion between contractors, labourers, government institutions, and the firm. I was also responsible for the firm's brand design.

BERNARD KHOURY / DW5 STUDIOS (BEIRUT, LEBANON)

Intern Architect . Intern UI Designer . 2013

I conducted an urban study of Beirut, and designed a user interface that allowed users to take part in the creation of a living and breathing map of the city through storytelling.

ABAR ARQUITECTOS (BARCELONA, SPAIN)

Intern Architect . 2012

Designed mass-producible, and customizable modular housing units based on humancentered design for a BIM software that would allow users to buy affordable housing.